Simon Goldin

Simon.Goldin@gmail.com

Experienced Software Engineer - NYC / Remote

Experienced full stack engineer with a focus on the front-end using modern tools and best practices across different industries. Experienced in different processes as well as management and mentoring, with a history of working with non-engineers to bring polished applications and features to B2B and B2C customers.

WORK EXPERIENCE

Staff	Frontend	Engineer
		Dashlane

Remote

Core front-end development of web applications and extensions in the internet security field relying on a zero-knowledge architecture, primarily focused on B2B products and features.

August 2022 to Present

Defining and iterating frontend architectures within a larger zero-knowledge architecture and context; much of this work involves cryptography, while other aspects of this work involves user experience and design.

Working, asynchronously when it's beneficial, with other stakeholders to iterate on existing processes to allow engineers, designers, and copywriters to improve velocity and visibility.

Defining and circulating best practices across the frontend engineering team; regular code reviewing, mentoring, and holding remote

ensemble-/pair-programming sessions with other engineers as well as

participating in and leading cross-functional efforts.

Always refactoring and improving.

Senior Frontend Engineer Dashlane

Remote **April 2022 to August 2022**

Short detour to the management track (below) before returning to the technical track. To preserve chronological order, this

Engineering Manager Remote

Managed 5 frontend engineers developing the B2B product, but ultimately decided to return to the technical leadership track.

November 2021 to April 2022

Senior Frontend Engineer Dashlane

New York, NY; Remote October 2019 to November 2021

Led development of underlying tools and dependencies including a custom component library (CSS-in-JS, React, TypeScript) and supporting documentation. Responsible for making application-wide improvements to code quality, long-term maintenance, and developer experience.

Led development on B2B products including zero-knowledge SSO/SCIM authentication.

Senior Full Stack Engineer TripleLift In addition to responsibilities below: mentorship of other engineers; wrote and discussed technical specifications across the team, improved workflow, processes, and developer experience.

New York, NY January 2018 to October 2019

Led a cross-team project to build a customized, reusable, and scalable component library leveraging Material UI (React, TypeScript).

Full Stack Engineer TripleLift

Developed and maintained a variety of applications in AngularJS, React (and TypeScript), PHP, Go, and NodeJS for internal and external users for campaign and creative management, as well as JS code used on publishers' sites.

New York, NY August 2015 to January 2018

Heavily involved in application architecture decisions as well as hiring, code reviews, providing business context to engineers, and technology context to non-engineering teams.

Software Engineer Worked with management and designers to develop a test preparation studying

play2prep New York, NY August 2013 to July 2015 mobile app for iOS and Android phones and tablets using Cordova, Grunt, Bower, NPM, AngularJS, SCSS, Java, and Apache Thrift.

Programmer TMCBonds LLC.

New York, NY October 2010 to August 2013 Implemented solutions to improve developer and user experience and features with JavaScript and ExtJS; Supported monthly releases; Monitored stability of website supporting \$150M in daily trades. Led development of mobile application using Sencha Touch and pre-existing Java backend.

Web Developer Rutgers University Piscataway NI

Piscataway, NJ January 2009 to October 2010 Helped develop the official Rutgers School of Engineering website and other Drupal-based sites for Rutgers University. Took on system administration roles in a LAMP (PHP) server environment.

Web Developer Freelance

April 2007 to August 2015

Developed websites using WordPress, Drupal, vanillaJS and jQuery, as necessary for a particular project. Followed strict deadlines to complete projects to client specifications for small businesses and organizations. Often worked concurrently on multiple websites to create production code from sketches and mockups (PDFs, PSDs, pen & paper, etc).

EDUCATION

Rutgers University School of Engineering New Brunswick, New Jersey Bachelor of Science in Computer and Electrical Engineering, May 2010 Electrical Engineering; Digital Signal Processing, Sensors & Networking Systems.

TECHNICAL EXPERIENCE

Languages & Frameworks: React, NodeJS; unit testing with Jest, React Testing Library, others; Emotion, styled-components, CSS-in-JS, LESS & SCSS; HTML5 & CSS3; TypeScript, JavaScript, NPM/Yarn/PNPM, PHP, Java, Go, MySQL, MongoDB.

Software & Tools: Mac OS X, Windows, Linux; debugging tools (Chrome & FireFox DevTools, xdebug); git, gitlab, github; Intellij IDEA/WebStorm, vim; Photoshop, Illustrator; comfortable with sysadmin tasks and command line tools; AWS; Single-Page Applications (SPA), Multi-Page Applications (MPA), Server-Side Rendering (SSR), Browser Extensions.